Guide to the Charles F. Bates Papers
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Research Files, 1874-1970; Series III; 5; (13 boxes)
  - CHARLES F. BATES
    - Other Papers
      - Family Papers, 1937, 1970, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 157-58)
  - ELIZABETH BACON CUSTER
    - Correspondence
      See also: Series I and II; Box 13, folder 176
      - 1876-1928, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 159)
    - Personal Papers
      - Will, n.d (Box 13, Folder 160)
      - Miscellaneous, 1890, 1925 (Box 13, Folder 161)
    - Writings
      - 1897-1927, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 162)
    - Histories/Biographies
      - 1882-1933, 1933, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 163)
  - GEORGE ARMSTRONG CUSTER
    - 1861 Investigation
      - Notes, 1935 (Box 13, Folder 164)
    - 1867-68 Investigation
      - Charges against Custer, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 165)
      - Custer's defense, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 166)
      - Testimony, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 167-69)
      - Newspaper accounts, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 170)
      - Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 171)
    - Correspondence
      - 1858-71, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 172-77)
    - Personal Papers
      - Miscellaneous, 1874 (Box 13, Folder 178)
    - Writings
      - 1866-74, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 179)
    - Histories/Biographies
      - 1864-1936, undated, 1931, n.d. (Box 13, Folder 180-86)
        See also: Oversize, Box 26, folder 419-20
    - Other Papers
      - Biographical notes, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 187-88)
      - Family papers, 1912, 1933, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 189)
      - Poems, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 190)
      - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 191)
        See also: Oversize, Box 26, folder 421
  - EDWARD S. GODFREY
    - Official Papers
      - Seventh Cavalry records
        See: Oversize, Box 27, folder 438
      - West Point records, 1879-83 (Box 14, Folder 192)
      - Miscellaneous, 1881-91, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 193)
    - Personal Papers
      - Diary (extracts) 1876, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 194)
      - Financial papers, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 195)
      - Medal of Honor Legion of the United States of America, 1909, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 196)
      - See also: Box 22, folder 330
      - Order of the Indian Wars, 1910-31, n.d. (Box 14, Folder 197-98)
      - Order of the Indian Wars, 1917-26 (Box 15, Folder 199)
      - Scrapbook, 1875-1908 (Box 15, Folder 200)
      - Scrapbook: detached material, 1908, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 201)
      - Miscellaneous, 1929 (Box 15, Folder 202)
        See also: Oversize, Box 26, folder 422
    - Writings
      - Writings of 1876, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 203)
      - "Custer's Last Battle, (1891)": galleys, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 204)
      - "Custer's Last Battle": misc., n.d. (Box 15, Folder 205)
      - Writings of 1903-1930, 1928, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 206)
      - "A Citizen Army": draft n.d. (Box 15, Folder 207)
      - [Description of Little Big Horn Battle], n.d. (Box 15, Folder 208)
      - Undated (Box 15, Folder 209)
    - Histories/Biographies
      - 1926-33, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 210)
    - Other Papers
      - Description of Godfrey Collection, Library of Congress, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 211)
      - Family papers, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 212)
  - MARCUS RENO
    - 1879 Investigation
      - Court Records, 1883, 1921, n.d. (Box 15, Folder 213-15)
      - Testimony, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 216-27)
      - Contemporary newspaper accounts: 1879 Jan-Mar
        See: Oversize, Box 27, folder 439
    - Histories/Biographies
      - 1927, undated (Box 16, Folder 228)
  - NINETEENTH-CENTURY ARMY-INDIAN CAMPAIGNS
    Army-Indian Campaigns is further subdivided by year, and within each year material is organized into the following groups: (1) Army orders-communications, (2) Contemporary newspaper accounts, (3) Army-Government Reports, (4) Personal Accounts by participants, (5) Histories, and (6) Other Papers or Miscellaneous. Some material has been arranged under topical headings at the end of the series. Copies of originals are indicated by listing the date of the original in the folder description and placing "n.d." in the date position.
    - 1866 Campaign
      - Histories (Box 16, Folder 229)
    - 1867 Campaign
      - Army orders-communications: 1867 May-Aug (Box 16, Folder 230)
    - 1868 Campaign
      - Army orders-communications: 1868 Nov-Dec, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 231-32)
      - Contemporary newspaper accounts: 1868-1869, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 233)
        See also: Oversize, Box 27, folder 440
      - Personal accounts by participants: 1868-1909, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 234)
      - Histories: undated (Box 16, Folder 236)
      - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 16, Folder 237)
    - 1869 Campaign
      - Army orders-communications: 1869 Jan-Apr, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 238)
      - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 239)
    - 1873 Campaign
      - Army orders-communications: 1873 Aug- Sept, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 240)
    - 1874 Campaign
      - Army-orders communications: 1874 Jun, Dec (Box 17, Folder 241)
      - Army-Government Reports: 1875 (Box 17, Folder 242)
    - 1875 Campaign
      - Army orders-communications: 1875 Jan, Nov (Box 17, Folder 243)
      - Contemporary newspaper accounts: 1875
        See: Oversize, Box 27, folder 441
    - 1876 Campaign
      - Army orders-communications: 1876 Feb-Dec (Box 17, Folder 244-48)
        See also: Oversize, Box 26, folder 423
      - Contemporary newspaper accounts: 1876, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 249)
        See also: Oversize, Box 27, folder 442-43
      - Army-Government Reports: 1876 Sep, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 250)
      - Personal accounts by participants: 1876-1926, 1910, n.d. (Box 17, Folder 251-53)
        See also: Oversize, Box 26, folder 424
      - Personal accounts by participants: 1927-33, 1929-30, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 254)
      - Personal accounts by participants: undated (Box 18, Folder 255-56)
      - Personal accounts by participants: undated, unknown (Box 18, Folder 257)
      - Histories: 1886-1947, undated, 1900-47, n.d. (Box 18, Folder 258-65)
        See also: Oversize, Box 28, folder 444
    - Other Papers
      - Miscellaneous notes, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 266-69)
      - Fiction, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 270)
      - The Flaming Frontier (movie), n.d. (Box 19, Folder 271)
      - They Died With Their Boots On (movie)
        See: Oversize, Box 26, folder 425
    - 1877 Campaign
      - Army orders-communications, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 272)
      - Contemporary newspaper accounts: 1877
        See: Oversize, Box 26, folder 426
    - 1878 Campaign
      - Army orders-communications: 1878, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 273)
      - Army-Government Reports: 1878, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 274)
    - 1895 Campaign
      - Army orders-communications: 1895, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 275)
    - Campaigns-General
      - Contemporary newspaper accounts: 1875-76, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 276)
        See also: Box 16, folder 200
      - Histories: 1881, undated, 1881, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 277-78)
    - Other Papers
      - Government bill, 1927 (Box 19, Folder 279)
      - "Catalogue of American Indian War Photographs" (Historical Section, Army War College) (Box 19, Folder 280)
      - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 281)
    - Indians
      - Histories: 1868-1938, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 282)
        See also: Oversize, Box 28, folder 445
    - Seventh Cavalry
      - Histories: 1925, undated, 1925, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 283)
  - REVIEWS OF BOOKS ON CUSTER AND LITTLE BIG HORN
    - 1876?: Frederick Whittaker's [Biography of Custer], n.d. (Box 19, Folder 284)
    - 1896: Colonel Hughes's "The Campaign against the Sioux 1876" ( Journal of Military Institute, Jan): galley (Box 19, Folder 285)
    - 1923: Homer W. Wheeler's Buffalo Days, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 286)
    - 1925: E. A. Brininstool's A Trooper with Custer, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 287)
    - 1926: W. A. Graham's The Story of Little Big Horn, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 288)
    - 1931: A Warrior Who Fought Custer, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 289)
    - 1934: Frederick Van de Water's Glory Hunter (Box 19, Folder 290)
    - 1935: 103 Fights and Scrimmages (Box 19, Folder 291)
    - 1936: Fred Dustin's The Custer Fight (Box 19, Folder 292)
    - 1944: Ernest Haycox's Bugles in the Afternoon, n.d. (Box 19, Folder 293)
  - CUSTER MONUMENT AND TWENTIETH-CENTURY OBSERVANCES
    - Histories: 1908 (Box 20, Folder 294)
    - Newspaper clippings: 1910-39, undated (Box 20, Folder 295-302)
    - Miscellaneous, 1910-47 (Box 20, Folder 303)
- Background Material, 1882-1977; Series IV; 0.5; (2 boxes)
  Series IV, Background Material, contains primary and secondary research material related to, but broader than Bates's research. The files are arranged alphabetically with miscellaneous material at the end. Copies of originals are indicated by listing the date of the original in the folder description and placing "n.d." in the date position.
  - American West
    - Histories: 1923-29, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 304)
    - Histories: Winners of the West, newspaper series 1926-39
      See: Oversize, Boxes 28-29, folders 447-52
  - Belknap, William W., n.d. (Box 21, Folder 305)
    See also: Oversize, Box 29, folder 453
  - Camp, Walter Mason, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 306)
  - Civil War
    - Army orders-communications: 1863-65, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 307)
    - Histories: 1883-1938 (Box 21, Folder 308-10)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1977, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 311-13)
  - Grant, Ulysses, n.d (Box 21, Folder 314)
    See also: Box 21, folder 323
  - Hamilton, Alexander (Box 21, Folder 315)
  - "Heroes of the World": radio show
    - Scripts: 1929 (Box 21, Folder 316)
    - Scripts: 1930 (Box 21, Folder 317)
  - Hutchinson, Anne, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 318)
  - Lawrence, William V., n.d. (Box 21, Folder 319)
  - Lincoln, Abraham, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 320)
  - Monroe County, Michigan, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 321)
  - Oklahoma Historical Society, 1932 (Box 21, Folder 322)
  - Porter, Fitz John, 1882 Dec (Box 21, Folder 323)
  - Ramseur, Stephen D., 1920, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 324)
  - Reynolds, J. J.
    See: Oversize, Box 26, folder 428
  - Schofield, John M., 1929 (Box 21, Folder 325)
  - Sheridan, Philip Henry, n.d. (Box 21, Folder 326)
  - Somervell, Brehon Burke, 1942 (Box 22, Folder 327)
  - Terry, Alfred H., n.d. (Box 22, Folder 328)
  - U.S. Army
    - Histories: 1883-1942, undated, 1883-1942, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 329)
    - Legislation, 1915, 1925,n.d. (Box 22, Folder 332)
    - Miscellaneous notes, 1889, 1922 (Box 22, Folder 333)
  - Wilson, Woodrow, 1941, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 334)
  - Miscellaneous articles, 1915, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 335)
  - Miscellaneous papers, n.d. (Box 22, Folder 336)
    See also: Oversize, Box 26, folder 429
- Photographs and Illustrations, 1866-1935; Series V; 0.5; (2 boxes)
  Series V, Photographs and Illustrations, contains original nineteenth-century photoprints, a tintype, stereographs, reproductions, and a variety of illustrations produced by photographic and photomechanical reproduction.
  - BATES FAMILY
    - Bates, Alexander [Philemon]
      - Portrait, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 337)
    - Bates, Charles Francis
      - Portraits, ca. 1890, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 338-39)
    - Harman, Anna Bates
      - Portrait, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 340)
  - CUSTER FAMILY
    - Custer, Elizabeth Bacon
      - Portraits, [1860s], n.d. (Box 23, Folder 341-42)
      - Posing with Maggie Custer Calhoun, Thomas Custer, Agnes Bates Wellington, [1875], n.d. (Box 23, Folder 343)
      - Posing with others in Egypt
        See: Oversize, Box 26, folder 430
    - Custer, George Armstrong
      - Portraits, [1861], ca.1873 (Box 23, Folder 344-45)
        See also: Oversize, Box 26, folder 431
      - Posing with Others
        - Custer and Elizabeth Bacon Custer, 1874, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 346)
        - Custer, Elizabeth Bacon Custer, and Thomas Custer (Box 23, Folder 347)
        - Custer, family, and friends outside Custer home in Austin, Texas, [1866] (Box 23, Folder 348)
        - Custer and Agnes Bates Wellington, [1875] (Box 23, Folder 349)
        - Custer and Grand Duke Alexis of Russia, [1872], n.d. (Box 23, Folder 350)
        - Custer and Maj. Gen. Alfred Pheasonton (Box 23, Folder 351)
        - Camp on Big Creek near Fort Hays, ca. 1867 (Box 23, Folder 352)
        - Fort Lincoln residence, ca. 1875, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 353)
        - [Fort Lincoln] picnic, Little Heart River, [1875], n.d. (Box 23, Folder 354)
        - Group posing in front of a house, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 355)
        - Bear hunting, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 356)
        - Buffalo hunting party, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 357)
      - Miscellaneous
        - Custer's horses Vic and Dandy (Box 23, Folder 358)
        - Custer's name carved in a rock, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 359)
    - Custer, Thomas
      - Portrait, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 360)
      - Posing with Maggie Custer Calhoun and Agnes Bates Wellington, ca. 1875 (Box 23, Folder 361)
  - INDIVIDUALS
    - Calhoun, Capt. James, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 362)
    - California Joe, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 363)
    - Cook, Lt. William W., n.d. (Box 23, Folder 364)
    - Godfrey, Edward S., n.d. (Box 23, Folder 365)
    - Martin, Sgt. John, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 366)
    - Parkhurst, Col., n.d. (Box 23, Folder 367)
    - Scott, Winfield, 1864 (Box 23, Folder 368)
    - Sitting Bull, n.d. (Box 23, Folder 369)
    - Smith, Lt. A. E., n.d. (Box 23, Folder 370)
    - Terry, Gen. A. H., n.d. (Box 23, Folder 371)
    - Two Moon, Chief, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 372)
    - White-Man-Runs-Him, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 373)
    - Yates, Capt. G. W., n.d. (Box 24, Folder 374)
  - GROUP POSES
    - Indians at Pine Ridge Indian Agency, Fort Niobrara, Nebraska
      See: Oversize, Box 26, folder 432
    - Officers of the 7th Cavalry, Co. G, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 375)
    - Officers of the 7th Cavalry in 1868 Washita campaign, [1868], n.d. (Box 24, Folder 376)
    - Officers of the 7th Cavalry, Fort Lincoln, 1875, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 377)
    - Members of the 7th Cavalry in 1874, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 378)
    - Dramatic image of 7th Cavalry, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 379)
  - PLACES AND MONUMENTS
    - Black Hills, South Dakota, 1874 expedition, 1874, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 381)
    - Custer monuments, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 383)
    - Fort Riley, Kanas
      See: Oversize, Box 30, folders 454-55
    - Little Big Horn Region, Montana, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 384)
    - Reno entrenchments monuments, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 385)
    - Sioux camp, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 386)
    - U.S. Army Corps, Manilla, 1935 (Box 24, Folder 387)
  - BATTLE IMAGES
    - "The Circle Attack," painting by Charles Schreyvogel, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 388)
    - [Civil War]
      See: Oversize, Box 26, folder 433
    - "Custer's Demand," painting by Charles Schreyvogel
      See: Oversize, Box 26, folder 434
    - [Custer's Last Stand] painting by James E. Taylor
      See: Oversize, Box 26, folder 435
    - "Discovery of Men of the Kidder Party," painting by J. E. Taylor
      See: Oversize, Box 26, folder 436
    - "We Circle all Around Him," painting by Ernest L. Blumensehein (Box 24, Folder 389)
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 390)
  - MISCELLANEOUS
    - Unidentified individuals (Box 24, Folder 391)
    - Unidentified groups, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 392)
    - Unidentified place
      See: Oversize, Box 26, folder 437
    - Miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 24, Folder 393)
      See also: Oversize, Box 30, folder 456
- Maps, 1874-1930; Series VI; 2; (1 box)
  Series VI, Maps, contains original maps and photoreproductions probably collected by Bates for use in his research. The material has been divided into Geographical West and Gettysburg-Antietam, both arranged chronologically.
  - GEOGRAPHICAL WEST
    - Raynold's Map and Editions
      ...Map of the Yellowstone and Missouri Rivers and their tributaries explored by Capt. W. F. Raynolds Topl. Engrs. and 1st Lieut. H. E. Maynadier 10th Infy. Assistant, 1859-60. To accompany a report to the Bureau of Topographical Engineers, U. S. War Department.
      - Original in boards: (Cover title: Montana and Dakota by Capt. Raynolds). (scale 1:1200000, size 68.2 x 108.6 cm.), 1869 Nov 19 (Box 25, Folder 394)
      - Photoreproductions of original. (Scale 1:1200000, two copies: size 34.2 x 53.6 cm. and 35.3 x 54 cm.) (Box 25, Folder 395)
      - 1877 Edition, title continues: revised and Enlarged by Major G. L. Gillespie, U.S. Engr's, Bvt. Lt. Col. U.S.A. Chief Engr. Military Division of the Missouri, 1876. Published by authority of the Hon. the Secretary of War, Office of the Chief of Engineers, U.S. Army. (scale 1:1200000, size 78.1 x 100 cm.) (Box 25, Folder 396)
      - 1877 Edition with notes: Map Showing Many Battlefields of the Indian Wars and Trail of the Big Horn and Yellowstone Expedition of 1876 by Brig. Gen. W. C. Brown, U.S.A., Retried and General Charles King, Denver, Colorado. Reproduced by the Clason Map Co. (scale 1:1200000, size 77.3 x 100.6 cm.), 1930 (Box 25, Folder 396a)
    - Map of the Military Department of the Platte, Wyoming. Compiled under the direction of Captain Wm. A. Jones, Corps of Engineers, Omaha, Nebraska. Drawn by Louis von Froben. (scale 1:1200000, size 41.2 x 68.6 cm.), 1874 (Box 25, Folder 397)
    - Geological Map of Western Wyoming illustrating the Report of Mr. Theo. B. Comstock. Geologist of the Military Reconnaissance in that Region conducted by Capt. W. A. Jones, Corps of Eng's, U.S.A., 1873. Published by authority of the Hon. Secretary of War in the Office of Engineers, U.6S. Army. (scale 1:600000, size 76.24 x 43.5 cm.), 1874 (Box 25, Folder 397a)
    - [Wyoming]. (n.s., size 22.1 x 21.1 cm.), ca. 1880 (Box 25, Folder 398)
    - [Hand-drawn map of Monte Christo Flat, Wyoming]. (n.s., size 33.4 x 25.5 cm.) (Box 25, Folder 398a)
    - Sketch of White River Country by Lt. S. A. Cloman act'g Eng'r Officer Div. of the Missouri for Capt. Godfrey, 7th Cav'y. (n.s., size 30.6 x 24.3 cm.), [ca. 1890] (Box 25, Folder 399)
    - Map of the Department of Dakota including Minnesota, North Dakota, Montana, Yellowstone National Park, and that portion of South Dakota Lying North of the Forty-Fourth Parallel of North Latitude prepared by authority of Brigadier General Wesley Merritt in the Engineer Office Hdqrs. Dept. Dakota. Compiled and Drawn under the direction of Lieut. Haydn S. Cole 3rd Inf. A.E.O. by H. F. Strebe Topographical Asst., U.S.A. (scale 1:101376, size 91.6 x 167.8 cm.), 1891 (Box 25, Folder 400)
    - Montana Custer Battlefield U.S. Geological Survey George Otis Smith Director, R. B. Marshall, Topographer, Surveyed in 1891. (two copies, scale 1:5280, size 37.5 x 30 cm., 49.8 x 40.9 cm.), 1908 Sep (Box 25, Folder 401)
    - Montana Fort Custer Sheet, U.S. Geological Survey, George Otis Director, A. H. Thompson, Geographer, Frank Tweedy Topographer in charge, edition of June 1894, reprinted Mar 1915, Standard Map Co. distributors. (scale 1:125000, size 44.7 x 31.4 cm.) (Box 25, Folder 402)
    - Map of Crow Indian Reservation Montana, Department of the Interior, Office of Indian Affairs, compiled and drawn by Frazer C. Hilder, C.E., revised by Albert Henderson. (scale 1:2534, 1912 edition, size 23.9 x 32.2 cm., 1921 edition, size 35.8 x 52.8 cm.), 1921, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 403)
    - Map showing Campaigns against the Sioux and Cheyenne Indians in Montana in 1876. Compiled and drawn by L. C. Rennick, Crow Agency, Montana. (scale 1:3800160, size 64.4 x 109 cm.), 1921 Nov. (Box 25, Folder 404)
    - [Hand-drawn Map of Custer Battlefield National Cemetery, land given Indians, land patented or sold] by F. K. for Supt. A. (n.s., size 30.6 x 30.5 cm.), 1921 Jun 2 (Box 25, Folder 405)
    - Trails made and Routes taken by the Fourth U.S. Cavalry under command of General R. S. MacKenzie in its operations against hostile Indians in Texas, Indian-Territory (now Oklahoma), New Mexico and Old Mexico during the period of 1871-2-3-4 and 5, compiled from military and other surveys, prepared by E. D. Dorchester. (scale 1:1505437, size 44.8 x 41.3 cm.), 1927 (Box 25, Folder 406)
    - Map of the Trans-Mississippi Territory of the United States during the period of the American Fur Trade as conducted from St. Louis between the years 1807 and 1843, Showing the Location of Indian Tribes, Trading Posts, Routes of Travel and other features of interest. Drawn by Paul Burgoldt, copyrighted 1901 by Francis P. Harper. (scale 1:7793280, size 41.6 x 42 cm.) (Box 25, Folder 407)
    - Map of route of Big Horn Expedition August 15 to September 30, 1874, Companies B and D 2d Cav., F, H and M 3d Cav., H 4th Infy and D 13th Infy commanded by Capt. Anson Mills, 3d Cav. Drawn by C. Page, Pvt. Co. M 3d Cav. (scale 1:1267200, size 31.5 x 26 cm.) (Box 25, Folder 408)
    - ...Territory of Montana, 1876, Department of the Interior, General Land Office, S. S. Burbett commissioner Compiled from the Official Records of the General Land Office and other sources by C. Roeser, Principal Draughtsman G.L.O., Photo lith & print by Julius Bien. (scale 1:1267200, size 39.2 x 53 cm.) (Box 25, Folder 409)
    - Map of the Line of March of the Troops Serving in the Department of Dakota in the Campaign against Hostile Sioux, 1876 Brig. Gen'l A. H. Terry Comdng. Lt. E. Maguire, Chief Engineer Drawn in the Chief Engineers Office, H'd Q'rs, Dep't of Dakota by James E. Wilson, Serg't, U.S. Eng'rs. (scale 1:760320, size 46 x 129.1 cm.), n.d. (Box 25, Folder 410)
    - [Handdrawn Map showing 1876 battle sites, rivers, and Indian agencies]. (scale 1:63360, size 91.8 x 96.5 cm.) (Box 25, Folder 411)
    - Custer Battlefield Fac-simile, on reduced scale, from Custer Battlefield, Montana, quadrangle U.S. Geological Survey (1891). (scale 1:36206, size 30.9 x 26.2 cm.), n.d. (Box 25, Folder 412)
    - [Maps of 1876 Expedition], 1931, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 413)
    - Topographical maps, n.d. (Box 25, Folder 414)
  - GETTYSBURG-ANTIETAM
    - Strategic Map of Gettysburg-Antietam
      Made by direction of Major J. F. Morrison, General Staff, U.S.A., Senior Instructor, Department of Engineers, in Charge. Photographic reduction...U.S. Geological Survey. Draftsman M.S.E. J. Howry, Army Service Schools Detachment. Photographer R.S.M. F. Arganbright, Lithographer R.Q.- M.S. F. Janes. (scale 1:63360)
      - Taneytown Rectangle. (size 43.6 x 67.5 cm.) Chambersbury Rectangle. (size 43.7 x 67.3 cm.) Gettysburg Rectangle. (size 44.3 x 67.8 cm.), 1910 (Box 25, Folder 415)
    - [Topographical Maps of Gettysburg-Antietam]
      Reduced from 12 in. War Game Map by the Engineer Dept., Army Service Schools, Fort Leavenworth, Kas.
      - Scale 1:21120, size 171.6 x 184.1 cm. 1913 (Box 25, Folder 416)
- Oversize, 3; (5 boxes)
  Oversize contains material from Series III, IV, and V and in a parallel arrangement.
  - RESEARCH FILES
    - Charles F. Bates
      - Personal Papers: flag (48 stars), n.d. (Box 26, Folder 417)
      - Writings: 1927: "General Custer and the Indians in the Battle of Little Big Horn" (Box 26, Folder 418)
    - George Armstrong Custer
      - Histories/Biographies: 1864, [1875], 1864, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 419-20)
      - Other Papers: miscellaneous, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 421)
    - Edward S. Godfrey
      - Personal Papers: miscellaneous, 1929 (Box 26, Folder 422)
    - Nineteenth-Century Army-Indian Campaigns
      - 1876 Campaign
        - Army orders-communications: 1876 Feb-Dec, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 423)
        - Personal accounts by participants: 1878-1898, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 424)
        - Other Papers: They Died With Their Boots On (movie), 1940 (Box 26, Folder 425)
      - 1877 Campaign
        - Contemporary newspaper accounts: 1877, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 426)
    - Custer Monument and 20th Century Observances
      - Miscellaneous, 1931, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 427)
  - BACKGROUND MATERIAL
    - Reynolds, J. J., n.d. (Box 26, Folder 428)
    - Miscellaneous papers, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 429)
  - PHOTOGRAPHS AND ILLUSTRATIONS
    - Custer Family
      - Custer, Elizabeth Bacon: Posing with others in Egypt, n.d. (Box 26, Folder 430)